number five asks which proton is most
acidic with this concept of strength of
acidity more acidic less acidic we're
always looking at the stability of the
conjugate base that is produced so when
we lose a proton we're going to have a
minus charge what happens to that minus
charge what kind of atom is it sitting
on is it delocalized how much is it
delocalized the more delocalized the
more stable that anion is going to be
all of these hydrogens are sitting on
carbon atoms so there's no difference
there we're comparing carbon ions but
then we're saying is there any
delocalization that can occur there for
example if we're looking at this one
over here if we lose that proton we're
going to have a minus charge on this
carbon atom there is a little bit of
delocalization that can occur we would
be able to push that over here and then
this could be pushed up there so there
is some delocalization that could happen
there and we'll say that there is some